A Guide to the United States Circuit Court (5th Circuit) Court records, 1790-1882
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
United States Circuit Court (5th Circuit). Court records, 1790-1882
The Library of Virginia
25186
116 cu. ft. (239 boxes) and 45 volumes
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
These materials are available on microfilm and should be served instead of the originals:
Series I: Ended cases, restored, 1790-1800 (Misc. reels 658-669)
Series III. Index to ended cases, 1790-1861 (Misc. reel 3959)
Series VI. Fee books, 1835-1843 (Misc. reel 3943)
Series VII. Order books, 1790-1831 (Misc. reels 3944-3948)
Series VIII. Record books, 1791-1834 (Misc. reels 3949-3958)
Series IX. Rule books, 1790-1845 (Misc. reel 812)
Acquisition Information
Transferred to the Library by the authority of and in accordance with an Order in the United States District Court for the Eastern District of Virginia, Richmond, Virginia, 6 March 1952.
Biographical Information
The Circuit Court for the District of Virginia was set up under the Judiciary Act of 1789. The court had both original and appellate jurisdiction. The original jurisdiction was concurrent with Statute courts in all suits of civil nature both at common law and equity where the amount in controversy exceeded $500 and where the United States was a plaintiff. The circuit court also had jurisdiction over all suits involving major criminal offenses against the laws of the United States, all suits where an alien was a party, and all suits between citizens of different states. It also reviewed the decrees of the district courts in civil actions where the amount in controversy was more than $500. The appellate jurisdiction of the court was transferred to the newly created circuit courts by an act of 3 March 1891 (26 Stat. 826), which established a circuit court of appeals (United States Court of Appeals) in each circuit. The Judicial Code of 1911 abolished the circuit courts as of 1 January 1912, and transferred their remaining jurisdiction and records to the district courts. [U.S. National Archives and Records Administration: U.S. District Courts Finding Aid, Virginia, 2001]
Scope and Content
Records, 1790-1882, of the 5th Circuit of the United States Circuit Court (now United States Court of Appeals for the Fourth Circuit) including case files, docket books, execution books, fee books, order books, record books, and rules books. Of note are the Ended Cases, 1790-1882, which include bills of complaint, affidavits, depositions, subpoenas, and other papers filed with the court. Cases of note include United States vs. Aaron Burr (1807), United States vs. Jefferson Davis (1865-1868), and George Washington Custis Lee vs. Frederick Kaufman et als (1877-1882), regarding Arlington Estate, the Lee family home. Records also include indictments of John C. Breckinridge (1866) and of various Confederate officers (1865) which are located with the Jefferson Davis records.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I. Ended cases, restored, 1790-1882
Series II. Ended cases, unrestored, 1790-1861
Series III. Index to ended cases, 1790-1861
Series IV. Docket books, 1819-1828
Series V. Execution books, 1791-1805
Series VI. Fee books, 1835-1843
Series VII. Order books, 1790-1831
Series VIII. Record books, 1791-1834
Series IX. Rule books, 1790-1845
Contents List
- Series I. Ended cases, restored,, 1790-1882., Extent: 38 boxes and 2 volumes on shelf. (Box 1-36a)
  These records include bills of complaint, answers, affidavits, depositions, reports of special masters, writs of injunctions, warrants and subpoenas, exhibits and other papers filed with the court. The Ended cases are organized by Restored (conserved) and Unrestored (not conserved). The Restored Ended Cases have been conserved, barrowed, and are bound in pamphlet cases. An index is available to all the Ended cases (also available on Misc. reel 3959). Cases of note include: United States vs. Aaron Burr (1807); John Mercer et als vs. Selden's extx et als. (1840); United States vs. Jefferson Davis (1865-1868); and George Washington Custis Lee vs. Frederick Kaufman et als. (1877-1882).
  Arranged in two subseries by box size and within each subseries chronologically. Subseries 1: Legal size, Subseries 2: Oversize.
  - Subseries 1. Restored.
    - Ended cases, restored, 1790-1791. (Box 1 (Also on Misc. reel 658-659))
    - Ended cases, restored, 1792. (Box 2 (Also on Misc. reel 659))
    - Ended cases, restored, 1793 A-D. (Box 3 (Also on Misc. reel 659-660))
    - Ended cases, restored, 1793 D-G. (Box 4 (Also on Misc. reel 660))
    - Ended cases, restored, 1793 H-T. (Box 5 (Also on Misc. reel 661))
    - Ended cases, restored, 1793 U-Z; 1794 A-C. (Box 6 (Also on Misc. reel 661-662))
    - Ended cases, restored, 1794 C-H. (Box 7 (Also on Misc. reel 661-662))
    - Ended cases, restored, 1794 H-R. (Box 8 (Also on Misc. reel 662-663))
    - Ended cases, restored, 1794 S-Z; 1795 A-B. (Box 9 (Also on Misc. reel 663))
    - Ended cases, restored, 1795 B-D. (Box 10 (Also on Misc. reel 663-664))
    - Ended cases, restored, 1795 D-H. (Box 11 (Also on Misc. reel 664-665))
    - Ended cases, restored, 1795 I-R. (Box 12 (Also on Misc. reel 665))
    - Ended cases, restored, 1795 S-Z; 1796 A-B. (Box 13 (Also on Misc. reel 665-666))
    - Ended cases, restored, 1796 B-F. (Box 14 (Also on Misc. reel 666-667))
    - Ended cases, restored, 1796 G-Z. (Box 15 (Also on Misc. reel 667))
    - Ended cases, restored, 1797. (Box 16 (Also on Misc. reel 667-668))
    - Ended cases, restored, 1798-1800. (Box 17 (Also on Misc. reel 668-669))
    - Ended cases, restored, 1801-1804 U. (Box 18)
    - Ended cases, restored, 1804 V-1806 C. (Box 19)
    - Ended cases, restored, 1806 D-W. (Box 20)
    - Ended cases, restored, 1806 W-1812. (Box 21)
    - Ended cases, restored, 1813-1820. (Box 22)
    - Ended cases, restored, 1821-1824 A-G. (Box 23)
    - Ended cases, restored, 1824 H-Z; 1825-1831. (Box 24)
    - Ended cases, restored, 1832 A-P. (Box 25)
    - Ended cases, restored, 1832 P-Z; 1833-1840. (Box 26)
    - Ended cases, restored, 1869, U.S. vs. Jefferson Davis (box includes indictments of John C. Breckinridge and of various Confederate officers). (Box 27)
    - Ended cases, restored, 1877-1882, G.W.C. Lee vs. Frederick Kaufman et als.; and G.W.C. Lee vs. Austin Branham et als. (Box 28)
    - Ended cases, restored, 1879 G.W.C. Lee vs. Frederick Kaufman et als. (photostat volume). (Volume on shelf)
  - Subseries 2. Restored, oversize.
    - Ended cases, restored oversize, 1792-1794. (Box 29)
    - Ended cases, restored oversize, 1794-1796. (Box 30)
    - Ended cases, restored oversize, 1797-1802. (Box 30a)
    - Ended cases, restored oversize, 1803-1806. (Box 31)
    - Ended cases, restored oversize, 1807. (Box 32)
      U.S. vs. Aaron Burr
    - Ended cases, restored oversize, 1807. (Volume on shelf)
      U.S. vs. Aaron Burr (photostat volume)
    - Ended cases, restored oversize, 1806-1814. (Box 33)
    - Ended cases, restored oversize, 1818-1832. (Box 34)
    - Ended cases, restored oversize, 1840. (Box 35)
      John Mercer et als vs. Selden's extx et als.
    - Ended cases, restored oversize, 1865-1868. (Box 36)
      U.S. vs. Jefferson Davis (volume includes indictments of John C. Breckinridge and of various Confederate officers)(photostats and bound photostat volume; originals in Box 27)
    - Ended cases, restored miscellaneous envelopes. (Box 36a)
- Series II. Ended cases, unrestored, 1790-1861., Extent: 201 boxes. (Box 37-237)
  These records include bills of complaint, answers, affidavits, depositions, reports of special masters, writs of injunctions, warrants and subpoenas, exhibits and other papers filed with the court. The Ended cases are organized by Restored (conserved) and Unrestored (not conserved). The Unrestored Ended Cases are not conserved and should be handled with care. An index is available to all the Ended cases (also available on Misc. reel 3959).
  Cases of note include: Archibald Freeland vs. Heron, Lenox and Company (1809); Archibald and Jon Hamilton surviving partners vs. Williams executrix and Clay (1821); J.J. Tucker vs. Marine Insurance Company of Norfolk (1823); and Miller vs. Grinnan's executor (1858). Also of note are the Clerk of Court Correspondence, 1829-1857.
  Arranged in three subseries by box size and within each subseries chronologically. Subseries 1: Legal size, Subseries 2: Oversize File I; and Subseries 3: Oversize File II.
  - Subseries 1. Unrestored.
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1791-1796. (Box 37)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1797 A-B. (Box 38)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1797 B-C. (Box 39)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1797 D-H. (Box 40)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1797 I-S. (Box 41)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1797 T-Z. (Box 42)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1798 A-D. (Box 43)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1798 D-J. (Box 44)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1798 K-Z. (Box 45)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1799 A-B. (Box 46)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1799 C-H. (Box 47)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1799 J-P. (Box 48)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1799 R-Z. (Box 49)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1800 A-D. (Box 50)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1800 F-L. (Box 51)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1800 M-S. (Box 52)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1800 T-Z. (Box 53)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1801 A-F. (Box 54)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1801 G-P. (Box 55)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1801 R-Z. (Box 56)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1802 A-C. (Box 57)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1802 H-P. (Box 58)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1802 R-Z. (Box 59)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1803 A-H. (Box 60)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1803 H-Z. (Box 61)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1804 A-D. (Box 62)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1804 E-K. (Box 63)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1804 L-Z. (Box 64)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1805 A-H. (Box 65)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1805 J-P. (Box 66)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1805 R-Z. (Box 67)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1806 A-L. (Box 68)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1806 M-Z. (Box 69)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1807 A-H. (Box 70)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1807 H-M. (Box 71)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1807 O-Z. (Box 72)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1808 A-H. (Box 73)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1808 H-M. (Box 74)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1808 M-Z. (Box 75)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1809 A-H. (Box 76)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1809 H-M. (Box 77)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1809 M-Z. (Box 78)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1810 A-G. (Box 79)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1810 H-P. (Box 80)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1810 R-Z. (Box 81)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1811 A-G. (Box 82)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1811 H-Z. (Box 83)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1812 A-H. (Box 84)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1812 J-Z. (Box 85)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1813. (Box 86)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1814. (Box 87)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1815 A-R. (Box 88)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1815 S-Z. (Box 89)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1816 A-L. (Box 90)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1816 M-Z. (Box 91)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1817 A-G. (Box 92)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1817 H-Z. (Box 93)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1818 A-F. (Box 94)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1818 G-S. (Box 95)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1818 T-Z. (Box 96)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1819 A-E. (Box 97)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1819 F-H. (Box 98)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1819 O-Z. (Box 99)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1820 A-B. (Box 100)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1820 B-F. (Box 101)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1820 G-K. (Box 102)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1820 L-R. (Box 103)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1820 S-Z. (Box 104)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1821 A-E. (Box 105)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1821 G-M. (Box 106)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1821 M-W. (Box 107)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1821 W-Z. (Box 108)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1822 A-B. (Box 109)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1822 C-S. (Box 110)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1822 T-Z. (Box 111)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1823 A-D. (Box 112)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1823 E-G. (Box 113)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1823 H-Z. (Box 114)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1824 A-D. (Box 115)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1824 D-H. (Box 116)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1824 H-T. (Box 117)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1824 W-Z. (Box 118)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1825 A-R. (Box 119)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1825 S-Z. (Box 120)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1826 A-L. (Box 121)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1826 M-Z. (Box 122)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1827 A-M. (Box 123)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1827 R-Z. (Box 124)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1828 A-L. (Box 125)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1828 M-Z. (Box 126)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1829 A-H. (Box 127)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1829 H-Z. (Box 128)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1830 A-U. (Box 129)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1830 U-Z. (Box 130)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1831 A-B. (Box 131)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1831 B-M. (Box 132)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1831 M-Z. (Box 133)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1832 A-S. (Box 134)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1832 S-Z. (Box 135)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1833 A-L. (Box 136)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1833 M-Z. (Box 137)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1834. (Box 138)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1835 A-C. (Box 139)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1835 C-Z. (Box 140)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1836-1837. (Box 141)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1838. (Box 142)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1839. (Box 143)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1840. (Box 144)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1841. (Box 145)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1842. (Box 146)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1843 A-P. (Box 147)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1843 P-Z. (Box 148)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1844. (Box 149)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1845 A-K. (Box 150)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1845 P-Z. (Box 151)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1846. (Box 152)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1847. (Box 153)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1848. (Box 154)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1849-1851. (Box 155)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1852-1854. (Box 156)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1855. (Box 157)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1856. (Box 158)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1857 A-T. (Box 159)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1857 U-Z. (Box 160)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1858 A-J. (Box 161)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1858 K-Z. (Box 162)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1859 A-H. (Box 163)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1859 H-Z. (Box 164)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1860. (Box 165)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, 1861. (Box 166)
    - Ended cases, unrestored, nd. (Box 167)
      Miscellaneous
    - Ended cases, unrestored, Clerk of Court correspondence, 1829-1857. (Box 167a)
  - Subseries 2. Unrestored, Oversize File I.
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1794-1798. (Box 168)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1798-1800. (Box 169)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1800-1804. (Box 170)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1805-1807. (Box 171)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1807-1808. (Box 172)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1808-1809. (Box 173)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1809-1810. (Box 174)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1809. (Box 175)
      Archibald Freeland vs. Heron, Lenox and Company
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1810. (Box 176)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1811. (Box 177)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1811-1812. (Box 178)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1812-1813. (Box 179)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1813-1814. (Box 180)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1814-1815. (Box 181)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1816-1817. (Box 182)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1817. (Box 183)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1817-1818. (Box 184)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1818-1819. (Box 185)
      NOTE: Item, "A Confession of Faith," 1743, from Baptist Association v. Hart's EXOR, 1819, was taken from this box, has been conserved, and can be located in Infolinx as record barcode #0007421142.
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1819. (Box 186)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1820. (Box 187)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1820-1821. (Box 188)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1821. (Box 189)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1821-1822. (Box 190)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1821. (Box 191)
      Archibald and Jon Hamilton surviving partners vs. Williams executrix and Clay
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1822. (Box 192)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1822-1823. (Box 193)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1823. (Box 194)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1823-1824. (Box 195)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1825-1826. (Box 196)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1826-1827. (Box 197)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1827-1829. (Box 198)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1831-1832. (Box 199)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1832. (Box 200-202)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1833-1834. (Box 203)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1836-1838. (Box 204)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1838-1840. (Box 205)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1841-1843. (Box 206)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1844-1846. (Box 207)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1846. (Box 208)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1848-1849. (Box 209)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1849-1853. (Box 210)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1853-1857. (Box 211)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1857-1859. (Box 212)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1858. (Box 213)
      Miller vs. Grinnan's executor, files 1-5
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1858. (Box 214)
      Miller vs. Grinnan's executor, files 6-10
  - Subseries 3. Unrestored, Oversize File II.
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1793-1798. (Box 215)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1799-1804. (Box 216)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1804-1805. (Box 217)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1806. (Box 218)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1807. (Box 219)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1808-1810. (Box 220)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1810-1812. (Box 221)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1813-1816. (Box 222)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1816-1817. (Box 223)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1817-1818. (Box 224)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1819-1820. (Box 225)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1820-1821. (Box 226)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1822-1823. (Box 227)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1823. (Box 228)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1823. (Box 229)
      J.J. Tucker vs. Marine Insurance Company of Norfolk
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1824-1826. (Box 230)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1826-1827. (Box 231)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1827-1830. (Box 232)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1830-1831. (Box 233)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1832. (Box 234)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1833-1846. (Box 235)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1853-1857. (Box 236)
    - Ended cases, unrestored oversize, 1857-1857. (Box 237)
- Series III. Index to Ended Cases, 1790-1861., Extent: 2 volumes on shelf. (Volume on shelf)
  These volumes index all the ended cases, 1790-1861, restored and unrestored. The index is also available on microfilm, Misc. reel 3959.
  - Index to Ended Cases (original), 1790-1861. (Volume on shelf (Also on Misc. reel 3959))
  - Index to Ended Cases (negative photostat), 1790-1861. (Volume on shelf (Also on Misc. reel 3959))
- Series IV. Docket book, 1819-1828., Extent: 2 volumes on shelf. (Volume on shelf)
  The volume entries include the name and number of the case, nature of the case, name of attorneys, court costs, and a chronological list of filings and proceedings in the case. Also included is an index.
  - Docket book, 1819 May-1828 May. (Volume on shelf)
  - Docket book, Index. (Volume on shelf)
- Series V. Execution books, 1791-1805., Extent: 2 volumes on shelf. (Volume on shelf)
  The volume entries include the date of the case, kind of action, name of attorney and names of parties in the case, amount of the debt, to whom the execution was delivered and information about its return to the court, including the date of the return by the officer of the court. Each volume contains an index at the end of the volume.
  - Execution book, 1791 November-1798 February. (Volume on shelf)
  - Execution book, 1797 December-1805 February. (Volume on shelf)
- Series VI. Fee book, 1835-1843., Extent: 1 volume on shelf. (Volume on shelf)
  The volume entries include a chronological listing of all fees collected by the court for filing costs, attorney fees, taxes, and copies of documents. Each entry includes the name of the case, list of fees, and short description of fees collected.
  - Fee book, 1835 May-1843 November. (Volume on shelf (Also on Misc. reel 3943))
- Series VII. Order books, 1790-1831., Extent: 13 volumes on shelf. (Volume on shelf)
  The volume entries include copies of orders and decrees in all types of cases. The information shown includes the date of the order, case title, and the name of the judge issuing the order.
  - Order book No. 1, 1790 May-1795 June. (Volume on shelf (Also on Misc. reel 3944))
  - Order book No. 2, 1795 November-1797 June. (Volume on shelf (Also on Misc. reel 3944))
  - Order book No. 3, 1797 November-1800 December. (Volume on shelf (Also on Misc. reel 3944))
  - Order book No. 4, 1801 April-1804 June. (Volume on shelf (Also on Misc. reel 3945))
  - Order book No. 5, 1804 November-1806 June. (Volume on shelf (Also on Misc. reel 3945))
  - Order book No. 6, 1806 November-1807 December. (Volume on shelf (Also on Misc. reel 3946))
  - Order book No. 7, 1808 May-1809 June. (Volume on shelf (Also on Misc. reel 3947))
  - Order book No. 8, 1809 November-1811 June. (Volume on shelf (Also on Misc. reel 3947))
  - Order book No. 9, 1811 November-1816 June. (Volume on shelf (Also on Misc. reel 3947))
  - Order book No. 11, 1820 November-1824 December. (Volume on shelf (Also on Misc. reel 3948))
  - Order book No. 12, 1825 May-1831 June. (Volume on shelf (Also on Misc. reel 3948))
  - Order book, Lexington, 1801-1802. (Volume on shelf)
- Series VIII. Record books, 1790-1869., Extent: 21 volumes on shelf. (Volume on shelf)
  The volume entries include a summary of each case, date of the case, case title, name of attorney and names of parties in the case, verdict, and settlement amount.
  - Record book No. 1A, 1790 November-1793 November. (Volume on shelf (Also on Misc. reel 3949))
  - Record book No. 2B, 1793 November-1794 November. (Volume on shelf (Also on Misc. reel 3949))
  - Record book No. 3C, 1794 November-1795 November. (Volume on shelf (Also on Misc. reel 3950))
  - Record book No. 4D, 1795 November-1797 November. (Volume on shelf (Also on Misc. reel 3950))
  - Record book No. 5E, 1796 May-1797 June. (Volume on shelf (Also on Misc. reel 3951))
  - Record book No. 6F, 1797 May-1798 November. (Volume on shelf (Also on Misc. reel 3951))
  - Record book No. 7G, 1798 November. (Volume on shelf (Also on Misc. reel 3952))
  - Record book No. 8H, 1797 November-1800 May. (Volume on shelf (Also on Misc. reel 3952))